HAMZA SHAIKH

https://hamza960.github.io/Personal-Portfolio-new/

shaikhhamzasaleem960@gmail.com

+91 9604195840 Pune, India

Summary:

I bring extensive experience as both a full-stack and frontend developer, specializing in widely-used frameworks like Laravel and React.js, making me an ideal candidate for any web application development role. I excel at understanding and addressing customer requirements, ensuring satisfaction, prioritizing critical tasks, and adhering to project timelines, consistently delivering projects on or ahead of schedule. With 4 years of technical expertise, I am confident in my ability to effectively communicate with clients and dedicate my best efforts to every project I undertake.

Experience:

SBU Solutions – Web Developer Intern (May 2021 – Aug 2021):
 Jamiat Halal Trust Web Application - created the app from scratch using Laravel and re-made the app using React , Node.js and MongoDB on customer demand.

Jamiat Halal Trust is a non-government, not for profit organization playing a vital role for the presence and growth of Indian industries in the Global as well as Indian Market. Our unique services help companies penetrate in the global economy and establish themselves as a trusted brand for consumers.

- Created and implemented React App using functional component.
- Created APIs and web applications using Laravel framework.
- Attending customer calls and gathering the requirements.
- Technical Documentations
- Troubleshooting
- Code Versioning Git

Code Optimization

Innothoughts Systems – React JS Developer (Aug 2021 - Dec 2021):
 GuideMeDoc App - Created a MERN stack app using scratch for a client from Dubai.

GuideMeDoc is a hospital CRM created to meet the needs of providing suitable doctors with respect to patients requirements.

- Built and maintained reusable react components and responsive UI using bootstrap, designed the UI from Scratch based on the design provided.
- Used MongoDB for Data handling
- Created APIs using Node js
- Created several static websites using HTML, CSS, bootstrap and JavaScript.
- Followed agile methodology like scrum
- Code versioning tools like Git was used

3. IT Gurus Software – Developer (Jan 2022 – Mar 2024)

Access Expense UK - Over 100,000 people across the world use Access Expense to simplify the process and gain better control and visibility of their expenses.

- Created enhancements and customizations in the Access Expense App using React.js.
- Created and maintained UI components using React functional component
- Followed agile methodology like scrum
- Used code versioning tools like git and svn
- Handled tasks in JIRA
- Made several static websites using HTML CSS, Javascript and Bootstrap.

4. **Hexaware Technologies – Developer** (July 2024 - Current):

Esker - As esker uses Javascript for frontend, I have created and built multiple customizations in the Esker app based on the customer requirements.

Esker is a financing tool that enables the Office of the CFO to optimize working capital and cashflow management, improve decision-making, and achieve better business outcomes through secure and strategic AI technologies.

I have been trained under the AP (Accounts Payable) and OM (Order Management) modules of Esker and have performed different customizations and enhancements for different customers.

Customers I worked for:

Mundipharma

Under the leadership of Marc Princen, CEO, and other leaders within the organization, the Executive Committee is responsible for overseeing the business operations of Mundipharma and ensuring that optimal patient care is at the center of everything the company does.

Arizona Cardinals Football

The Arizona Cardinals are a professional American football team based in the Phoenix metropolitan area. The Cardinals compete in the National Football League as a member of the National Football Conference West division.

IMG Academy

IMG Academy is a world-leading sports education brand and preparatory boarding school located in Bradenton, Florida, focusing on holistic student-athlete development, offering programs in academics, athletics, and personal development, with options for on-campus and online experiences.

- Software customization using JavaScript and Esker scripting tool based on business requirements
- Technical documentation
- Agile Methodology
- Code versioning Git
- VS Code
- Customer interaction
- Team collaboration
- Troubleshooting

- Performance and code optimization
- Understanding the Esker environments

Education:

- Dastur Schools June 2010 to May 2016 (SSC Board 84%)
- Poona College June 2016 to May 2018 (HSC Board 60%)
- Abeda Inamdar Senior College June 2018 to May 2021 (BCA Science 9.6 CGPA)

Skills:

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Bootstrap
- SCSS
- Responsive Design
- React JS
- Redux
- React Redux
- Redux toolkit
- Laravel
- Node JS
- Express JS
- MySQL
- MongoDB
- PHP
- Performance Optimization
- Code Optimization
- Troubleshooting
- Code Versioning techniques
- Git
- GitHub
- JIRA
- Agile Methodologies
- SCRUM
- Documentation

- SVN
- UI / UX Design